# **ASEEF AHMED**

# Sr. Software Engineer & System Administrator

Address: 81/83, Road-4, Block-B, Niketon, Gulshan, Dhaka-1212

Mobile: 0199-223-6479

Email: aseefahmed@gmail.com

Web: aseefahmed.net

## **About Myself**

I am Zend Certified PHP Engineer (ZCPE) and fluent in English having more tha 9 years of working experience in web industry as a Sr. Engineer. My vission is to gain confidence and fame using my potential in the field of Web Development, and express my innovative creative skills for myself and my company.

#### **Employment**

# Fair Pattern Inc. (A USA Based Company)

**2015 - Present** 

Sr. Software Engineer

Building a social networking for entrepreneur in Laravel. Responsible for working on a range of projects and interacting on a daily basis with graphic designers, other talented back-end developers and QA Team. Worked as part of a multi-disciplinary team, carrying out ad-hoc tasks as requested by the IT Manager. Had daily meeting to ensure the application build for customer's precisely matched their requirements

#### **Nexus Web Consultancy Ltd.**

2010 - 2015

Sr. Web Developer

- Developing and maintaining the front end functionality of websites
- Participating in discussions with clients to clarify what they want.
- Designing prototypes for apps and websites
- Creating logos, banners and buttons for web sites.
- Writing cross browser compliant XHTML, CSS & JavaScript
- Simultaneously managing several databases and reporting tools
- Provide guidance to other team members on web development issues.
- Developing websites that have a consistent feel and look throughout all web properties
- Providing technical support to end users.
- Identifying and correcting software deficiencies
- Devising SEO strategies based around specific keywords

#### BJIT Ltd.(Bangladesh-Japan IT)

2008 - 2009

PHP Developer

My main responsibility is building flexible, modular and well tested JavaScript/HTMI/CSS based applications. Some of them require real time communication, so I have the luck to work with various Javascript frameworks. Along with that I'm using node to improve and speed up my workflow. Coding cross-browser web sites, I'm happy to say that I produce responsive apps.

#### **Professional Certification**

Zend Certified PHP ••••••
Engineer (ZCPE)

#### **Professional Course**

Red Hat Linux

#### **Programming Skills**

PHP
Laravel Framework

MySQL

CSS

Bootstrap

Ruby on Rails

#### Javascript Skills

Javascript
JQuery
React.JS
Node.JS
Angular.JS

# **Database Skills**

MySQL •••••

MongoDB

SQL Server

# Third Party API

Amazon

Payment Gateways

Google

Facebook

Twitter

#### **Evoknow (A USA Based Software Firm)**

2006 - 2008

Web Developer

As a web developer I had to work as a team member to develop robus web applicatio based on PHP, Javascript, CSS and many other Javascript frameworks along with MVC Framework.

# Education

**Computer Science & Engineering (CSE)** 

2001 - 2005

Jahangirnagar University CGPA: 3.21 (Out of 4)

**Masters in Business Administration (MBA)** 

2009 - 2010

Jahangirnagar University

Result: 60%

# Operating System

Linux

•••••

Mac

Windows

•••••

# **Version Control System**

Git

Gitbub.com

•••••

BitBucket.org

Project Management Tools

Jira

•••••

Microsoft Office 2010

**WEB**: www.aseefahmed.net